Professional and personal papers of Edwin Wolf 2nd LCP.EW2
Library Company of Philadelphia
- III. Scholarship, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
  - IIIa. Talks and Publications, Bulk, 1960-1988; 1895-1990
    - Publication: "Library of a Philadelphia Judge", 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Publication: "History of the Book in America", 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Publication: "Great American Book Collectors to 1800", 1971 June (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Publication: "Library of Edward Lloyd, VI", 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Publication: "Library Company of Philadelphia, The", 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Talk: "James Logan", 1973 January (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Publication: "James Logan of Stenton", 1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Publication: "James Logan, Scholarly Bookman", undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Talk: "James Logan", 1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Publication: "James Logan (1674-1751)", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Publication: "James Logan, Bookman Extraordinary", 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Publication: "James Logan's Correspondence with William Reading, Librarian of Sion College (London)", 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Publication: "Some Books of Early English Provenance in the Library Company of Philadelphia", 1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Talk/Publication: "James Logan, Colonial Philadelphia's Greatest Bookman", undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Talk: "James Logan", undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Publication: "Libraries Don't Get Degrees", 1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Publication: "Information Retrieval for the Year 1745", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Publication: "Midwife to a Phoenix", 1970 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Publication: "A 235-Year-Old Library Moves 235,000 Books", 1966 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Talk/Publication: "The Library Company of Philadelphia", undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Publication: "1774 Address to the King" (oversized), 1964 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Publication: "Rare Book Collectors", circa 1965 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Talk: "Books Then and Now", undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Talk: "Historian versus Rare Book Librarian", 1959 December (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Talk: Untitled (on the role of public libraries), circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Publication: "Franklin's Way to Wealth as a Printer", 1949, 1951, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Publication: "More Books From the Library of the Byrds of Westover", 1978 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Publication: "Medical Books in Colonial Philadelphia", 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Talk: "Libraries and Librarians", 1959 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Talk: "Sentimental Musings of a Librarian", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Talk: Untitled (on research libraries), 1960 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Publication: "Thoughts on Books and Libraries", 1963 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Talk: Untitled (on automation in research libraries), 1960s (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Publication: "Origins of Philadelphia's Self-Depreciation, 1820-1920", 1980 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Talk: "Peale's Philadelphia", 1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Publication: "Penn's Green Country Town", undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Talk: Untitled (on Philadelphia), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Publication: Epilogue, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Publication: "Philadelphia, the Renaissance City", 1982 April (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Talk: "The Prodigal Son in England & America: A Century of Change", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Publication: "The Prodigal Son in England & America: A Century of Change", 1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Talk/Publication: "The Prodigal Son in England & America", undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Talk: Remarks at Rodeph Shalom, Yom Kippur 1976, 1976 November 22 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Publication: Book review of American Independence, the Growth of an Idea, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Publication: Book review of The Americans: The Colonial Experience, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Publication: Book review of The American Jewish Album, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Publication: Book review of The Autobiography of Benjamin Franklin, a Genetic Text, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Publication: Book review of Benjamin Franklin, a Biography, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Publication: "The (American) Printing of the Definitive Treaty of Peace of 1783 Freed of Obfuscation", 1971 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Publication: "A Biographical Dictionary of Early American Jews", 1961 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Publication: Book review of A Book for Sixpence, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Publication: Book review of The Book-Peddling Parson, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Publication: Book review of Books and Book People in 19th Century America, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Publication: Book review of A Bibliography of Songsters Printed in America Before 1821, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Publication: Book review of The City of New York: A History Illustrated from the Collections of the Museum of the City of New York, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Publication: Book review of A Colonial Southern Bookshelf: Reading in the Eighteenth Century, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Publication: Book review of A Descriptive Checklist of Book Catalogues Separately Printed in America, 1693-1800, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Publication: Book review of Early Amerian Almanacs: The Colonial Bible, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Publication: Book review of European Americana: A Chronological Guide 1493-1776, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Publication: Book review of Forgotton Pioneer, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Publication: Book review of The Papers of Benjamin Franklin (Vols. 1-3), 1961 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Publication: Book review of The Papers of Benjamin Franklin (Vol. 4), 1962 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Publication: Book review of The Papers of Benjamin Franklin (Vol. 5), 1962 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Publication: Book review of Gladly Learn and Gladly Teach, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Publication: Book review of The Jews in the United States, A Pictorial History, 1654 to the Present, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Publication: Book review of The John Dunlap Broadside: The First Printing of the Declaration of Independence, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Publication: Book review of The Library at Mount Vernon, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Publication: Book review of The Middle Colonies and the Coming of the American Revolution, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Publication: Book review of Modern Book Collecting, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Publication: Book review of My Dearest Julia, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Publication: Book review of The Paper Makers, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Publication: Book review of The Perennial Philadelphians, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Publication: Book review of Philadelphia and the China Trade, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Publication: Book review of Political Satire in the American Revolution, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Publication: Book review of The Printed Book in America, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Publication: Book review of The 1764 Catalogue of the Redwood Library at Newport, Rhode Island, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Publication: Book review of Thirteen Colonial Americana and 76 United Statesicana, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Publication: "In the Mainstream of American Book Collecting", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Publication: Book review of Thomas J. Wise Centenary Studies, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Publication: Book review of Wanderings, 1978 December 10 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Publication: Book review of William Blake, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Publication: "Rosenbach, a Biography", 1960 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Talk: "Rosenbach", 1979, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Publication: "Dr. Rosenbach", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Publication: "Dr. Rosenbach", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Publication: "Scribelarian Publications at the Library Company of Philadelphia", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Publication: "Rosenbach, P. H. and A. S. W.", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Talk: "What is American About America?", 1960s (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Publication: Book review of The Literary History of Philadelphia, circa 1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Publication: "The Authorship of the 1774 Address to the King Restudied", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Publication: "A Signed American Binding on the First American Edition of Shakespeare", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Publication: "Should Librarians Stretch or Bow?", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Talk: "A Penny Apiece - Civil War Song Sheets, Envelopes, and Counterfeit Money", undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Publication: "Value and Worth of Rare Books", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Publication: Book review of Revolutionary Doctor, Benjamin Rush, circa 1966 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Talk/Publication: "Surprises in Rare Book Collectors in Philadelphia", undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Talk: "They Bought Books", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Publication: " United States Hotel by Duval after Quinton", 1978 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Publication: Book review of The American Printer, 1787-1825, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Publication: The Library Company of Philadelphia Annual Report, 1980, circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - List of publications by Wolf, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Talk: "Underground Classics", circa 1968 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Publication: "I'd Rather Be in Philadelphia", circa 1982 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Publication: "Abraham Simon Wolf Rosenbach", 1959 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Talk: "Golden Age of Philadelphia Book Production", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Bibliography - Edwin Wolf", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Publication: Foreward to "The All-Embracing Dr. Franklin", 1938 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Publication: Preface to Folklore Associates Book, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Publication: Research materials for Legacies of Genius, 1980s (Box 15)
    - Publication: Research materials for Legacies of Genius, 1980s (Box 16)
    - Publication: Research materials for From Gothic Windows to Peacocks, circa 1990 (Box 17)
    - Research notes on Allegheny College Library, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Reprint of Joe W. Kraus, "Book Collectors of Early American Libraries," Library Quarterly, 1973 April, circa 1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Letters regarding talk entitled "On the Shoulders of Giants," given at the American Library Association Midwinter Conference, casette tape recording of talk, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Various materials regarding the American Philosophical Society, 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Research note on Bensel, Charles, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Research files on Bentley, William (1759-1819), undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Issue of Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, including an article on Berkenmeyer, Wilhelm Christophe (1686-1751), 1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Reprint of article on Boswell, James (1740-1795), undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Photostat of list of books owned by Brown, Charles Brockden (1771-1810), undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Photocopied pages from History of the Church in Burlington, New Jersey, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Research notes and draft of article on Burns, Robert, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Research files on Byrd, William, 1960-1987 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy of list of books owned by Byles, Mather (1707-1788), undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies of card catalog of Carter, Robert (1663-1732), undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Index of titles and letters (Carter, Robert Wormsley), 1971, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Photocopy of list of books owned by Chew, Benjamin (1722-1810), undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Materials regarding Rare Book School at Columbia University, 1985-1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Research files on Collin, Nicholas (1746-1831), undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Typescript of 1741 newspaper advertisement regarding the sale of the library of Cummings, Archibald (died 1740), undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Photostat of list of books owned by Darlington, William (1782-1863), undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Materials regarding the Eighteenth Century Short Title Catalogue (1 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Materials regarding the Eighteenth Century Short Title Catalogue (2 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research notes on Emlen, Samuel (1730-1799), undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research notes on Growden, Joseph (died 1730), undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Research files on Hand, Edward (1744-1882), undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy of "A Colonial Reading List," published in Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, 1932, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy of pages from Harvard College in the Seventeenth Century, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Research files on Jefferson, Thomas (1743-1826), 1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Research files on Jewish agencies, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Photocopy of list of books owned by Johnson, Samuel (1696-1771), undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Research files on Madison, James (1751-1836), undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Photocopy of Joseph Towne Wheeler, "Reading and Other Recreations of Marylanders, 1700-1776," Maryland Historical Magazine, 1943, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy of Gordon W. Jones, "The Library of Doctor John Mitchell of Urbana," Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, 1968, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies of articles regarding the Mathers, published in American Antiquarian Society, 1910, 1922, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Photocopy of inventory list of Montgomery, John (died 1731), undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Photocopy of "Early Private Libraries in New England," originally published in American Antiquarian Society, 1907, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of "The First Public Library in New Haven," originally published in Papers of the New Haven Colony Historical Society, 1895, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of Act of Incorporation and By-Laws of the Newtown Library Company, and photocopied pages from Newtown Library: Under Two Kings, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Photocopied pages from History of the State of New York, 1937, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Research files on Norris, Isaac, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Photocopied research files on Norris, John Parker (1763-1841), undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Oxford University regarding Lyell Lecture readership and publication of book, 1983-1986 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Photograph prints of will and inventory of belongings of Palmer, John (died 1809), undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Photocopy of "Parochial Libraries in the Colonial Period", undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Photocopy of The Parochial Library of the Eighteenth Century in Christ Church, Boston, 1917, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Research files on Philadelphia, City of, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Various materials regarding Philadelphia Ink: A Literary Celebration, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Report and other materials on the Philadelphia Maritime Museum, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Research note on Price, Benjamin (died 1766), undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Research note on Proud, Robert (1728-1813), undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Typescript of inventory of law books owned by Reed, Joseph, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Photocopied pages from The Atlantic Frontier: Colonial American Civilization, regarding "Rensselaerswyck", undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Photocopy of will of Ridgeway, Jacob, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Reprint of Athenaeum Annals, regarding Ross, John (1729-1800), 1962 April (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Research files regarding Rush, Benjamin (1745-1813), 1973 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Photocopied pages from Collections of the New York Historical Society for the Year 1880, regarding Sharpe, John, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Letter from American Philosophical Society regarding Shippen, William, Jr. (1736-1808), undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Typescript of list of books owned by Shoemaker, Rebecca (born 1773), undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Photocopy of catalogue of Smith, Jeremiah (1759-1842), 1971 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Photocopy of Walter B. Edgar, "Notable Libraries of Colonial South Carolina," published in South Carolina Historical Magazine, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Photostat of list of books owned by Smith, Stanley S. (1750-1819), undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of "Library of John Tatham, A. D. 1700", undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding publication in U.S. News & World Report, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Research files regarding Colonial Virginia, including photocopies of articles published in William & Mary Quarterly, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Research files regarding Walcut, Thomas (1768-1840), 1970, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Research files regarding Winthrop, John, Jr. (1606-1676), undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of list of books owned by Witherspoon, John (1723-1794), undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and other materials regarding contribution to World Book Encyclopedia, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Research notes regarding Yeates, Jasper (1745-1817), undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Various files, "A", 1985-1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Reviews of Afro-Americana, 1553-1906, published by the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Various files, "B", 1980s (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Various files regarding the Binswanger family, 1988, 1991, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Various files, "C", 1949, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Various files, "D", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Various files, "E", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Various files, "F", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Various files, "G", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Various files, "H" and "I", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Reviews of At the Instance of Benjamin Franklin, circa 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Various files regarding history of printing, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Various files, "J" and "K", 1974-1985 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Various files, "L", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Notices and reviews regarding The Library of James Logan of Philadelphia, 1674-1751, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Various files, "M", 1980s (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Various files, "N" and "O", 1986-1990 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Various files, "P", 1980s (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Various files, "Q" and "R", 1952, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Review and other materials regarding Rare People and Rare Books, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Various files regarding A. S. W. Rosenbach and descriptive bibliography, 1933, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Various files, "S", 1980s (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Various files, "T" and "V", 1985-1988 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Various files, "W", 1985-1988, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Various files regarding the Wolf family, including tax and financial documents, 1985-1988 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Drafts of Edwin's autobiography, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Various files, "X," "Y," and "Z", 1987-1988, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Draft of autobiographical sketch, copy of Bedales Association newsletter, 1992, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Columbia Rare Book School: Letter from Michael Winship; bibliographies of music and sheet music, publisher's bindings, and other subjects, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Columbia Rare Book School: Typescripts of lectures by Edwin, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Publication: "Colonial Playbills," including research files and correspondence, 1971-1973, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Publication: "The First Books and Printed Catalogues of the Library Company of Philadelphia", circa 1954 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Publication: "Franklin's Library", undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Publication: "Gravelot as Designer of Engraved Portrait Frames", circa 1950 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Publication: "Great American Book Collectors to 1800," photocopied research materials, circa 1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Talk/Publication: Untitled (on Library Company of Philadelphia), circa 1967 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Publication: Book review of A Library for Younger Schollers, circa 1961 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Talk/Publication: Untitled (on William Penn, book merchant), undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Publication: "Philobiblon", circa 1991 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Talk given at the Philobiblon Club, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Talk/Publication: "The Prodigal Son," including research files and correspondence, 1970-1972, 1982, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Typescript of introduction written for 1987 edition of E. M. Sowerby's Rare People and Rare Books, circa 1987 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Talk: "Richard Heston Shoemaker, 1907-1970", 1971 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Talk: "The STC (1475-1640) component of the English Short Title Catalogue" and various conference materials, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Talk: "Why are antique bookcases filled with Chinese export porcelain?", 1988 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Winterthur Conference: Text of Edwin's presentation, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - From Gothic Windows to Peacocks: Printed folios, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "A History of the Jews in Philadelphia" serialized clippings scrapbook, 1954 (Volume 8)
    - Offprint/reprint correspondence: 21 letters between Edwin and J. C. Wylie, W. S. Dix, G. B. Oldham, James T. Babb, F. B. Adams, Alton H. Keller, L. W. Hanson, R. E. Spiller, R. N. Williams, William Targ, Judith Shapiro, Justin Turner, J. C. Cummings, L. Leman, M. A. McCorrison, A. Halpern, A. D. Wainwright, P. Mellon, K. Johnson, Rabbi R. Lupo, and Ms. Levinson, 1954 March 23-1965 July 29 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Offprint/reprint correspondence: Letters between Edwin and C. W. Fenninger, L. M. C. Smith, and J. Bennett Nolan, 1948-1950 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Talks and lectures correspondence: 8 letters between Edwin and Rabbi M. Berkowitz, J. F. Spahr, J. A. Ritter, Amy B. Yerkes, and E. P. Alexander regarding talk given at B'nai B'rith on The Jew in American History; typescripts of "An Address Before a Group of Friends of The University of Delaware at Luncheon on April 19, 1952", 1951 March 16-1952 April 25 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Talks and lectures correspondence: 15 letters between Edwin and Rabbi M. Berkowitz, J. F. Spahr, J. A. Ritter, Amy B. Yerkes, and E. P. Alexander; address given before The Grolier Club, 1952 January 8-1964 December 3, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Talks and lectures correspondence: 5 letters between Edwin and Ada Liveright, D. S. Wiesen, R. Samuel, and J. G. Gunmere, 1935 October 29-1979 November 16 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Talks and lectures correspondence: Letters between Edwin and M. C. Marshall and H. D. MacPherson, 1952 March 3-7 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Research requests: 10 letters between Edwin and Morris Wolf, Susan Sterling Towles, Melvin K. Whiteleather, Robert R. Wark, Bernard C. Meyer, Anne Francis, Levi G. Leatham, and Donald A. Low, 1930 December 19-1965 November 4 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Research requests: 7 letters between Edwin and New York Public Library, Frederick Goff, E. Mongan, J. H. Powell, L. Henke, Vincent Eaton, and C. Butterworth, 1947 March 7-1950 April 24 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - I-Tell-You, newsletter of the Rodeph Shalom Religious School, Purim issue; including a poem by Edwin, "The Syrian King", 1927 March (Item 1)
    - Camp Kennebec Year Book, 1925 (Item 2)
    - "The Kennebecamper" twentieth anniversary issue, 1926 (Item 3)
    - "The Kennebecamper", 1927 (Item 4)